A Guide to the William Faulkner Foundation Collection
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
William Faulkner Foundation Collection 1918-1958
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6074, 6074-a, 6074-b, 6074-c, 6074-d
ca. 10 ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols. (New York: Garland, 1986-1987).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with Special Collections prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
This collection of William Faulkner's manuscripts was originally deposited in the Library by the author on 11 June 1959. It remained in the Library as Mr. Faulkner's property until 19 December 1966, when, under the terms of Mr. Faulkner's will, the collection became the property of the William Faulkner Foundation. On 13 April 1970 the announcement was made that title to the collection had been deeded by the Foundation to the University of Virginia. Additions to the collection have been made at various times.
Scope and Content
The Collection includes holograph and typescript material from nineteen published novels, two unpublished novels, thirty-two published and ten unpublished short stories, twenty-five published and eight unpublished pieces of verse eight movie or television scripts, two miscellaneous manuscripts, three essays, five speeches, and twenty miscellaneous items.
Arrangement
The series and items have been arranged in the order used by Meriwether in his volume, The Literary Career of William Faulkner( Princeton, 1961). Where it has been impossible to follow Meriwether's system exactly, notes facilitating comparison of the present Guide to his book have been included. References to "Massey" are to Linton R. Massey's William Faulkner: "Man Working," 1919-1962, A Catlogue of the William Faulkner Collections at the University of Virginia Library (Charlottesville, 1968). The latter volume contains chiefly information on the printed William Faulkner materials held by Special Collections but has a section devoted to the manuscripts.
All items are accession 6074 except as otherwise noted. Abbreviations: p. (pages); R (rectos); V (verses); l. (leaves)
Contents List
- SERIES I: NOVELS
  - SECTION A: PUBLISHED
    - SOLDIER'S PAY., IA:1); Bound typescript volume 476 p. (476 R, O V) on 476 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      with autograph corrections.
    - MOSQUITOES., IA:2); Bound typescript volume 470 p. (466 R, 4 V) on 466 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - MOSQUITOES., IA:2); AM draft fragments. 46 p. on 44 l. (Box Box 1.)
    - [SARTORIS] FLAGS IN THE DUST., IA:3); Autograph manuscript. 237 p. (236 R, 1 V) on 236 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - [SARTORIS] FLAGS IN THE DUST., IA:3); Bound typescript volume, 593 p. (593 R, O V) on 593 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      with autograph corrections. Note: volume has been debound. Original covers are boxed.
    - THE SOUND AND THE FURY., IA:4); Autograph manuscript. 140 p. (146 R, 2 V) on 146 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      Note: pages 1 and 1a (which were not, however, the original first pages of the manuscript) were removed on the instructions of Mr. Faulkner on 11 July 1959. The original first page is presently in the Massey- Faulkner Collection (accession 6271-a). Page 5 was not received with the manuscript.
    - THE SOUND AND THE FURY., IA:4); Bound carbon typescript 408 p. (408 R, O V) on 408 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - THE SOUND AND THE FURY., IA:4); Carbon typescript, 23 p. (22 R, 1 V) on 22 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      "Appendix." (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey p. 225) [6074-a]
    - AS I LAY DYING, IA:5); Autograph manuscript. 108 p. (107 R, 1 V) on 107 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - AS I LAY DYING, IA:5); Bound carbon typescript volume. 267 p. (266 R, 1 V) on 266 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - SANCTUARY, IA:6); Autograph manuscript. 138 p. (137 R, 1 V) on 137 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - SANCTUARY, IA:6); Bound carbon typescript, 368 p. (358 R, 10 V) on 358 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      with autograph corrections. Note: versos contain portions of an autograph manuscript.
    - LIGHT IN AUGUST, IA:7); Autograph manuscript. 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - LIGHT IN AUGUST, IA:7; Typescript setting copy. 344 p. (344 R, 0 V) on 344 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - PYLON, IA:8); Autograph manuscript. 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 1.)
    - PYLON, IA:8); Typescript setting copy. 344 p. (344 R, 0 V) on 344 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - ABSALOM, ABSALOM!, IA:9); Autograph manuscript 2 p. (2 R, 0 V) on 2 l. (Box Box 1.)
      chronology.
    - ABSALOM, ABSALOM!, IA:9); Typescript 16 p. (16 R, 0 V) on 16 l. (Box Box 1.)
    - ABSALOM, ABSALOM!, IA:9); Typescript setting copy, 469 p. (463 R, 6 V) on 463 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
    - ABSALOM, ABSALOM!, IA:9); 35 p. (35 R, 0 V) on 35 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Certificates of limitation for the Haddon Craftsmen Limited Edition. 25 unsigned and 10 signed by the author.
    - THE UNVANQUISHED, IA:10); Autograph manuscript. 23 p. (23 R, 0 V) on 23 l. (Box Box 1.)
      An Odor of Verbena.
    - THE UNVANQUISHED, IA:10); Typescript 54 p. (54 R, 0 V) on 54 l. (Box Box 1.)
      An Odor of Verbena. with autograph corrections.
    - THE WILD PALMS, IA:11); Miscellaneous autograph manuscript portion. 3 p. (3 R, 0 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Wild Palms.
    - THE WILD PALMS, IA:11); autograph manuscript. 17 p. (16 R, 1 V) on 16 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Old Man. Several revisions of scattered passages.
    - THE WILD PALMS, IA:11); Typescript setting copy 387 p. (284 R, 3 V) on 384 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      Includes autograph corrections and miscellaneous front material. 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l.
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Typescript. 3 p. (3 R, 0 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Abraham's Children.
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Carbon typescript. 55 p. (54 R, 1 V) (Box Box 1.)
      Father Abraham. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 228, under " Spotted Horses. ") [6074-a]
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Carbon typescript. 51 p. (52 R, 0 V) on 51 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Father Abraham. incomplete. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 228, under Spotted Horses. ) [6074-a]
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Autograph manuscript. 10 p. (10 R, 0 V) on 10 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Fool About A Horse. (Meriwether no. 12, b, 1)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Typescript 21 p. (21 R, 0 V) on 21 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Fool About A Horse. with autograph corrections. (Meriwether no. 12, b, 2)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Carbon typescript 33 p. (0 R, 33 v) on 33 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Fool About A Horse. with autograph correction. (Meriwether no. 12, c, 2)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Autograph manuscript. 17 p. (17 R, 0 V) on 17 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Barn Burning (Meriwether no. 12, c, 1)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Typescript. 32 p. (32 R, 0 V) on 32 l. (Box Box 1.)
      Barn Burning (Meriwether no. 12, c, 2)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Carbon typescript. 32 p. (32 R, 0 v) on 32 l. (Box Box 1.)
    - THE HAMLET, August 1931; IA:12); 10 p. (5 R, 5 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 1.)
      The Hound. Printed copy from Harpers', p. 266-274. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Autograph manuscript 207 p. (207 R, 0 V) on 2067 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      The Hound. (Meriwether no. 12, d)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Autograph manuscript. 94 p. (87 R, 7 V) on 87 l. (Box Box 1.)
      The Hound. Miscellaneous pages, principally of revisions. (Meriwether no 12, e)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Typescript. 18 p. (18 R, 0 V) on 18 l. (Box Box 1.)
      The Hound. Miscellaneous portions. (Meriwether no. 12, f)
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Typescript 84 p. (84 R, 0 V) on 84 l. (Box Box 1.)
      The Hound. with autograph corrections. Miscellaneous portions. (Not listed in Meriwether; includes the 57 p. listed by Massey, p. 225) [6074-a]
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Carbon transcript. 35 p. (35 R, 0 V) on 35 l. (Box Box 1.)
      The Hound. Miscellaneous portions. (Not listed in either Meriwether or Massey) [6074-a]
    - THE HAMLET, IA:12); Typescript setting copy 611 p. (597 R, 14 V) on 597 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 1.)
      The Hound. Includes autograph corrections and miscellaneous front material. 8 p. (8 R, 0 V) on 8 l.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 24 p. (22 R, 2 V) on 22 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      Was with autograph correction. (Meriwether no. 13, a)
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 6 p. (5 R, 1 V) on 5 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 2.)
      Was portions. (Not listed in Meriwether, see Massey, p. 225)
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 21 p. (21 R, 0 V) on 21 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      The Fire and the Hearth, A Point of Law, with autograph corrections.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript. 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      The Fire and the Hearth, Gold Is Not Always.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript. 19 p. (19 R, 0 V) on 19 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 17 p. (17 R, 0 V) on 17 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      The Fire and the Hearth, An Absolution [ Apotheosis ] with autograph corrections.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 20 p. (20 R, 0 V) on 20 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      The Fire and the Hearth, with autograph corrections.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 22 p. (20 R, 2 V) on 20 l and 1 p. (2 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      The Fire and the Hearth, Chapters One and Two.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Carbon typescript 25 p. (24 R, 1 V) on 24 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      Pantaloon in Black, with autograph corrections.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 17 p. (17 R, 0 V) on 17 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      The Old People, with autograph corrections.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Carbon typescript. 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      The Bear.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 26 p. (18 R, 8 V) on 18 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      Delta Autumn, with autograph corrections.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript 17 p. (14 R, 3 V) on 14 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      Go Down, Moses, with autograph correction. Note: versos contain typescript of another version.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript. 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
      Go Down, Moses.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Carbon typescript. 17 p. (17 R, 0 V) on 17 l. (items a-g in one slipcase) (Box Box 2.)
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Chart 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Genealogical chart in pencil showing the McCaslin-Edmonds-Beauchamp connections.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Typescript setting copy 414 p. (411 R, 3 V) on 414 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 2.)
      Includes autograph corrections and miscellaneous front material. 3 p. (3 R, 0 V) on 3 l.
    - GO DOWN, MOSES, IA:13); Galley proof. 2 p. on 1 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 2.)
    - INTRUDER IN THE DUST, IA:14); Autograph manuscript. 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 2.)
      (Meriwether no. 14, a)
    - INTRUDER IN THE DUST, IA:14); Autograph manuscripts 9 p. (7 R, 2 V) on 7 l (Box Box 2.)
      Dialogue portions. (Meriwether no. 14, a)
    - INTRUDER IN THE DUST, IA:14); Original typescript 167 p. (138 R, 29 V) on 138 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Includes miscellaneous typescripts. 172 p. (138 R, 34 V) on 138 l. Note: some versos contain earlier versions. (Meriwether no. 14, b)
    - INTRUDER IN THE DUST, IA:14); Typescript setting copy 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. and 336 p. (316 R, 20 V) on 316 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 2.)
      Front material. Notes: some versos contain portions of another typescript. (Meriwether no. 14, c) Miscellaneous front material boxed. 3 p. (3 R, 0 V) on 3 l.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Autograph manuscript. 12 p. (12 R, 0 V) on 12 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Smoke
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, April 1932.; IA:15); 18 p. (9 R, 9 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Smoke, Printed copy from Harper's Magazine
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15) (Box Box 2.)
      Monk. see below (item IA:15 g, 2)
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Miscellaneous typescript. 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Hand Upon the Waters.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Typescript 31 p. (31 R, 0 V) on 31 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Hand Upon the Waters, with autograph corrections.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Typescript 30 p. (30 R, 0 V) on 30 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Hand Upon the Waters, with autograph corrections. (numbered 1-33; missing p. 25, 26, 28)
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Typescript 22 p. (20 R, 2 V) on 20 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Hand Upon the Waters, Tomorrow, with autograph corrections.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Carbon typescript 22 p. (22 R, 0 V) on 20 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Hand Upon the Waters, An Error in Chemistry, with autograph corrections.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Carbon typescript 29 p. (23 R, 6 V) on 23 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Knight's Gambit, with autograph corrections.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Miscellaneous typescript and carbon typescript pages 87 p. (50 R, 37 V) on 50 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Knight's Gambit with autograph corrections. Note: includes TMs fragment of A FABLE 1 p. on 1 l.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Carbon typescript 228 p. (157 R, 71 V) on 157 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 2.)
      Knight's Gambit, with autograph corrections. Note: some versos contain portions of another typescript. (not listed in Meriwether; see Massey p. 226) [6074-a]
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Typescript 1 p. (1 R, 0 V) on 1 l. and 38 p. (19 R, 19 V) on 19 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Smoke, setting copy; Printed copy from [ Doctor Martino and Other Stories ]
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, May 1937; IA:15); 10 p. (5 R, 5 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Monk, Printed copy from Scribner's, setting copy.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, 4 November. 1939; IA:15); 10 p. (5 R, 5 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Hand Upon the Waters, Printed copy from Saturday Evening Post, setting copy.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, 23 November. 1940; IA:15); 12 p. (6 R, 6 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 2.)
      Tomorrow, Printed copy from Saturday Evening Post, setting copy
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, June 1946; IA:15); 16 p. (8 R, 8 V) on 8 l. (Box Box 2.)
      An Error in Chemistry, Printed copy from Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine, setting copy.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Typescript 192 p. (161 R, 31 V) on 161 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 2.)
      Knight's gambit, with autograph revisions; setting copy.
    - KNIGHT'S GAMBIT, IA:15); Layout, proofs and samples 85 p. (56 R, 29 V) on 56 l. (Box Box 2.)
      For front material for the 1949 Random House edition of Knight's Gambit. (Meriwether no. 15, h and I)
    - REQUIEM FOR A NUN, Id:16); autograph manuscript 75 p. (38 R, 37 V) on 38 l. (Box Box 3.)
      Miscellaneous portions
    - REQUIEM FOR A NUN, Id:16); typescript and carbon typescript 380 p. (308 R, 72 V) on 308 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 3.)
      Miscellaneous portions with autograph corrections.
    - REQUIEM FOR A NUN, Id:16); setting copy 409 p. (284 R, 125 V) on 284 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 3.)
      With autograph revisions. Note: some versos contain portions of another typescript of Requiem, also with autograph revisions. Front material 6 p. (6 R, 0 V) on 6 l.
    - REQUIEM FOR A NUN, Id:16); Bound galley proof (galleys are cut in half). 185 p. (185 R, 0 V) on 185 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 3.)
    - REQUIEM FOR A NUN, Id:16); Galley proofs 226 p. on 134 l. (Box Box 3.)
      With attached sheet of typescript additions and with autograph corrections.
    - REQUIEM FOR A NUN, Id:16); Page proofs. 193 p. on 97 l. (Box Box 3.)
      (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [6074-a]
    - REQUIEM FOR A NUN, 11 July 1951; Id:16); LS, 6 p. (6 R, 0 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 3.)
      Lemuel Ayers to William Faulkner, enclosing notes for suggested revisions of Requiem. (Meriwether no. 16, g)
    - A FABLE, IA:17) (see also item IA:15f2); autograph manuscript 12 p. (12 R, 0 V) on 12 l. (Box Box 3.)
      Miscellaneous portions.
    - A FABLE, IA:17) (see also item IA:15f2); typescript and carbon typescript 229 p. (189 R, 47 V) on 182 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 3.)
      Miscellaneous portions with autograph corrections. Note: some versos contain earlier versions.
    - A FABLE, IA:17 (see also item IA:15f2); autograph typescript 665 p. (382 R, 283 V) on 382 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 3.)
      Miscellaneous portions with corrections. Note: versos contain parts of this and other manuscripts. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [6074-a]
    - A FABLE, IA:17) (see also item IA:15f2); Typescript setting copy 1074 p. (573 R, 401 v) on 573 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 3.)
      With autograph corrections and miscellaneous front material. 7 p. (7 R, 0 V) on 7 l. Note: some versos contain an earlier version. (Meriwether no. 17, c)
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Printed copy. 6 p. (3 R, 3 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 4.)
      Prelude.
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Printed copy. 142 p. (72 R, 70 V) on 72 l. (Box Box 4.)
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Typescript. 10 p. (9 R, 1 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 4.)
      Interlude.
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Printed copy. 26 p. (14 R, 12 V) on 14 l. (Box Box 4.)
      The Old People.
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Typescript. 4 p. (4 R, 0 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 4.)
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Printed copy 19 p. (11 R, 8 V) on 19 l. (Box Box 4.)
      The Bear Hunt with typescript and autograph additions.
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Typescript. 7 p. (6 R, 1 V) on 6 l. (Box Box 4.)
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Galley proof. 8 p. on 8 l. (Box Box 4.)
      Race at Morning.
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy; Typescript. 13 p. (12 R, 1 V) on 12 l. (Box Box 4.)
      Epilogue.
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Setting copy 17 p. (17 R, 0 V) on 17 l. (Box Box 4.)
      Front material, layout, and instruction. [6451]
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Page proof. 214 p. on 72 l. (Box Box 4.)
      [6451]
    - BIG WOODS, IA:18); Foundry proof. 211 p. on 211 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 4.)
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); Autograph manuscript. 10 p. (10 R, 0 V) on 10 l. (Box Box 4.)
      A Mule in the Yard [6451-a]
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); Typescript 10 p. (10 R, 0 V) on 10 l. (Box Box 4.)
      A Mule in the Yard, with autograph correction.
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); Typescript setting copy 491 p. (488 R, 3 V) on 488 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 4.)
      Includes autograph correction and front material, 10 p. (10 R, 0 V) on 10 l. [6451-a]
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); Miscellaneous typescript 310 p. (170 R, 140 V) on 170 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 4.)
      With autograph corrections. Note: some versos contain letters, parts of other manuscript (including portions of The Mansion) and an essay. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 171) [6074-a]
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); Galley proof. 119 p. on 199 l. (Box Box 4.)
      (Meriwether no. 19, d) [6451-a]
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); Page proof. 373 p. on 125 l. (Box Box 5.)
      (Meriwether no, 19, e) [6451-a]
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); Foundry proof. 461 p. on 461 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 5.)
      (Meriwether no. 19, f) [6451-a]
    - THE TOWN, IA:19); 4 p. (2 R, 2 V) on 1. (Box Box 5.)
      Specifications and print sample. (Meriwether no. 19, g) [6451-a]
    - THE MANSION, IA:20)(See also item IA:19d above); Typescript 1036 p. (597 R, 429 V) on 597 l. (Box Box 5.)
      With autograph corrections. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [6094-a] Note: some versos contain typescript of an unproduced television series. [6074-f]
    - THE MANSION, IA:20)(See also item IA:19d above); Typescript 602 p. (596 R, 6 V) on 596 l. Slipcase. (Box Box 5.)
      With autograph corrections. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [60734-b]
    - THE MANSION, IA:20)(See also item IA:19d above); Printer's galley proofs 154 p. on 154 l. (Box Box 6.)
      With corrections (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [60734-b]
    - THE MANSION, IA:20)(See also item IA:19d above); Author's galley proofs 153 p. on 153 l. (Box Box 6.)
      With corrections. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [6074-b]
    - THE MANSION, IA:20)(See also item IA:19d above); Page proofs. 436 p. on 146 l. (Box Box 6.)
      (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [6074-b]
    - THE MANSION, IA:20)(See also item IA:19d above); 28 p. on 28 l. (Box Box 6.)
      Preliminary material from above. (Not listed in Meriwether; see Massey, p. 226) [6074-b]
    - THE MANSION, IA:20)(See also item IA:19d above); Foundry proofs. 439 p. on 118 l. (Box Box 7.)
  - SECTION B: UNPUBLISHED
    - ELMER", IB:1); Miscellaneous autograph manuscript. 5 p. (4 R, 1 V) on 4 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - ELMER, IB:1); Typescript 125 p. (123 R, 2 V) on 123 l. (Box Box 7.)
      With autograph corrections. (Meriwether no. 1, b)
    - ELMER, IB:1); Miscellaneous typescript. 5 p. (5 R, 0 V) on 5 l. (Box Box 7.)
      (Meriwether no. 1, b)
    - ELMER, IB:1); Typescript. 2 p. (2 R, 0 V) on 2 l. (Box Box 7.)
      Portrait of Elmer Hodge. (Meriwether no. 1, b)
    - THE DEVIL BEATS HIS WIFE., >IB:2); Autograph manuscript, 3 p. (3 R, 0 V) on 3 l. (Box Box 7.)
- Series II: Short Stories
  - A: Published
    The manuscript of short stories that were later integrated into novels are kept with the other material from those novels; they therefore have no numbers below and are provided with references to their current locations among the longer works.
    - Ad Astra., Autograph manuscript, 11 p. (11 R, 0 V) on 11 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - All the Dead Pilots., Autograph manuscript, 11 p. (10 R, 1 V) on 10 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - An Artist at Home., Autograph manuscript, 13 p. (13 R, 0 V) on 13 l. (Box Box 7.)
      Barn Burning. See The Hamlet; The Bear. See Go Down, Moses; A Bear Hunt. See Big Woods.
    - Beyond., Typescript, 28 p. (27 R, 1 V) on 27 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Beyond., Autograph manuscript, 9 p. (9 R, 0 V) on 9 l. (Box Box 7.)
    - Black Music., Autograph manuscript, 11 p. (11 R, 0 V) on 11 l. (Box Box 7.)